the area of ai and machine learning
looks very intimidating and magical from
the outside from self-driving cars to
chatbots and even github co-pilot is
very easy to get impressed with what ai
can do and of course we should be
impressed when we see what can be done
using ai because it is awesome it is
mind blowing but we also have to
remember that ai isn't magic in fact the
more you work with ai the closer you are
to ai the less magical it will seem so i
wanted to make this video to pull back
the curtain a little bit in ai to see
how it works from a bird's eye point of
view today we are going to see that even
though we talk about artificial
intelligence there is very little
intelligence involved instead there is a
lot of data processing statistics
pattern recognition and just a lot of
numbers that does not sound of course as
sexy as artificial intelligence there
are not movies being made of data
processing and pattern recognition
machines taking over the world but even
though there is no intelligence it is
still an amazing almost magical thing
but also i hope that by the end of this
video you feel a little bit less
intimidated by ai and more curious about
it i made a tiny demo application where
we can drag and drop photos of different
objects or animals the app is going to
try to guess what is on the photo what
animal or what object is there so let's
take a look as you can see it works
pretty well also as you can see the
machine never says that is 100 sure of
anything and instead gives you a
confidence score
now let's try again but this time let's
choose less common objects and less
common animals and as you will see the
confidence score is going to start to
drop and the guesses are going to be all
wrong
now we might wonder why is this model
able to recognize some things super well
but some other things like my face not
so well the reason why it doesn't know
about everything is because the model
that we are using maybe hasn't seen
those images or that kind of object
before but hold on a second because now
you have to define what is that word
model because i keep saying model model
model what does that mean the model that
we are using right now is called mobile
net and mobile net was trained using
something called supervised learning
wonderful people took 50 000 photos of
all kinds of animals and objects and
hand labeled them and classified them in
totaling 1000 categories they said
basically this is a cat this is a dog
this is a shoe this is a cat again
another shoe so on and so on and so on
so for example they ended up with a
bunch of different dog photos dogs of
different breeds dogs of different
colors a photo from the face of the dog
a photo from the bomb of the dog from
looking up looking down all kinds of
photos of a dog so they took this group
of photos and they gave them to a
machine learning algorithm and they
basically say hey look in these photos
there is something that we humans call a
dog so please take a look at these
photos and draw your own conclusions
into what makes up a doc so the machine
learning algorithm went to work and
looked at each one of these photos but
not the way humans would but the way a
computer would looking at the image not
as an image but as data as numbers as
pixels trying to find patterns and
extract features to know what it is that
makes up a dog increasing and decreasing
the brightness of the photo to do
something called a convolution to try to
reduce a photo of a dog to its most
important features here you can see an
image of what this algorithm might see
while it's processing a beagle's photo
what the algorithm finds those features
those patterns of what makes up a dock
are just a lot of numbers and they are
what is saved into a model now this
process of looking at the image and
processing the image and extracting the
features that happen for each image for
each one of those 1000 categories in the
mobile net model that we are working
with this is why when we show a photo of
my face to the model it wouldn't know
what it is because the model wasn't
trained with those kinds of photos the
good news for us is that we are able to
extend the model a little bit to teach
it things that it doesn't know yet
because the model is already pretty good
at extracting features from images and
then making a prediction between a
thousand categories what we can do now
is take this extraction power and use it
to make the model predict between the
categories that we decide in this demo
that i prepared we can write down the
labels that we want to train our model
on and using the camera i will show to
the model the images that it needs to be
able to train so let's see if we are
able to train our model to distinguish
between a happy face and a sad face so
let's show the model first what a happy
face looks like
and now let's do the same with a sad
face
now we will wait a little bit for the
features to be extracted and for the
model to be trained and then we can test
and see if it works and booyah as you
can see it works like a charm awesome
and that's it for today i hope that this
video gave you a small little overview
of how machine learning sort of works
and i hope that by now you feel less
intimidated and more comfortable as you
can see it's not magic but still pretty
cool
now the thing is that here we are not
really doing machine learning by
ourselves because if you think about it
we are just using the models that
somebody else built and trained which i
don't think it's so bad when you are
getting started with ai actually if you
look at what many people are doing in
the ai space many of them are actually
using a model that somebody else built
what we're doing here today is basically
driving a car without knowing how the
engine works maybe it's fine to drive
the car around town it's not a problem
but if the car breaks down and you have
to open the hood this is when it's good
to know what the basics are and this is
when we talk about the sponsor of
today's video the korea startup agency
is recruiting 200 people to join a free
ai education program called year dream
school year dream school runs for 10
months teaches from the very basics of
programming to the advanced level such
as data engineering machine learning and
deep learning it is an intensive ai
education program that is almost
equivalent as to attending a four-year
college with a major in ai also the
students of a year dream school will get
to have field experience by working with
various startups solving real life tasks
there will also be parts of kaggle
competitions so after graduating from
these schools students will be competent
enough to get a job at a korean tech
company or to make their own ai startup
all of these 10 months of education are
a hundred percent free anyone under 39
years old that wants to learn about ai
can apply for this program regardless of
the education or career background
applications are open right now so click
the link below so you will be able to
know the behind the scenes of what makes
up the models and the machine learning
algorithms that we have been using today
thank you for watching as always let me
know in the comments if you would like
me to make more videos related to ai and
if you enjoyed the demos today let me
know if you would like a tutorial on
that because it turns out it's very easy
to build machine learning stuff in the
browser using just vanilla javascript
and ml5.js so if that is something you
are interested on let me know in the
comments as well thank you for watching
as always stay happy stay free stay
healthy eat kimchi come sammy dah salan
hail see you on the next one bye
you